You told me... "I'm no one...
I don't want to be anyone..."
（ナルト）お前は俺に　誰でもない
誰でもいたくないって言ったよな。
（オビト）やめろ！
俺の中に入ってくるな！
Stop! Don't come into my thoughts!
でも　本当は俺と一緒で
火影になりたかったんだな。
But the truth is... You wanted to become
the Hokage, just like me.
It could have even ended up
もしかしたら　俺は　アンタの後ろを
追っかけてた場合だって→
where I was chasing after
your shadow...
あったかもしれねえんだな。
since I've always wanted
to become the Hokage.
俺は　火影に憧れてるから。
I threw away the past
and my naïve self!
捨てきった過去と　甘い自分だ。
こんなものを…。
Then why am I able to see this?
なら　なんで俺に見えんだよ。
面して　自分隠したってダメだ。
You can't hide behind a mask.
アンタは　カカシ先生の友達で
父ちゃんの部下で→
You were Kakashi Sensei's friend...
my dad's subordinate...
サスケと同じ　うちはで
俺と同じ夢持つ先輩で→
an Uchiha like Sasuke...
and a shinobi of the Hidden Leaf
who had the same dream as me.
木ノ葉の忍だった。
何なんだいったい…。
What...
お前は俺をどうしたい！？
What exactly do
you want with me?!
アンタは　うちはオビトだってことだ。
To remind you that
you are Obito Uchiha.
言ったろ　ぜってぇ　その面
ひっぺがしてやるってよ！
I told you, didn't I?
I swore I'd tear that mask
right off your face!
Obito Uchiha
Obito Uchiha?
うちはオビトだと？
今更　その名に　その存在に
何の意味がある？
What meaning is there
in that name...
in that existence, now?
十尾と融合した今　俺は
超越者として悟りに至ったのだ。
I have merged with Ten Tails.
I have transcended and
attained enlightenment.
つまり　俺はもう　人ではない。
I am no longer human.
次の段階へと人々を導く者。
I will guide mankind to
the next stage.
六道仙人と意志　体を同じくする
第二の六道仙人だ。
I possess the same will and body
as the Sage of Six Paths.
I am the Second Sage
of the Six Paths!
Wrong! You are Obito Uchiha!
違う！　お前は　うちはオビトだ！
When our chakra touched earlier,
I saw your past.
さっき　チャクラがくっついて
お前の過去が見えた。
Our personal histories and
アンタと俺は　生い立ちも
火影　目指したのも一緒だ。
our dream of becoming Hokage
are the same.
本当にそっくりだ。
Almost exactly alike.
Neither of us knew our parents.
両親を知らなかったことも→
And we both lost people
precious to us.
自分にとって大切な人が
いなくなったのも。
Which is why you tried
to scare me
だから　いちばん怖いのが
孤独だって　俺を脅した。
by saying solitude is
my worst nightmare.
アンタも　最初は誰かに認められ
褒めてもらいたかった。
In the beginning,
you too wanted to be acknowledged
and praised by others!
That's why you wanted
to be Hokage...
それが欲しくて
火影を目指したはずだ！
俺と同じなら。
If you're the same as me, that is!
アンタの今を見てみろよ！
But look at you now!
忍すべてを敵にして→
You've turned all shinobi
into enemies
and you go spouting
some nonsense
世界のためだとか何だとか
へ理屈こねて→
that you're doing it for
the sake of the world...
自分の都合で
やってるだけじゃねえか！
when you're only doing it
for yourself!
誰からも…　その大切な人からも
認めてもらえねえんだよ。
No one...
not even those
precious to you
would ever acknowledge
this current dream of yours.
今の夢は！
俺と同じ夢持ってたアンタが→
You used to have
the same dream as me.
火影とは真逆になっちまった。
But now you've become
the exact opposite of a Hokage!
俺とソックリだったからこそ…。
いや…。
It's because you're just
like me that...
No, it's because of that....
だったからこそ　俺は　この世界に
絶望するお前を見てみたかった。
That I wanted to see you despair
about this world.
いや　もう一度
実感したかったんだ。
Or...I suppose I wanted
to feel again for myself,
俺自身の進むべき道が
間違っていないことを。
that the path I have chosen
for myself is not a mistake.
お前と戦っていると　お前は
かつての俺を思い出させた。
When I was fighting you,
you made me recall my youth.
だから試したくなったのだ。
That's why I started wanting
to test you.
ソックリだったお前が
いつ絶望するのかと。
To see when you,
someone who's just like me,
would fall to despair...
今までの思いを捨てきるまで。
and abandon your feelings, your past.
俺は　ソックリだったからこそ
ムカつくんだ！
It's because we were so alike
that I'm pissed off!
お前が！　全部捨てて
逃げてるだけじゃねえかよ！
You're just...abandoning everything
and running away!
いや　俺のやっていることは
火影となんら変わらない。
No...
What I'm doing is no different
from a Hokage's actions.
それ以上だ。
平和を実現できるのだからな。
In fact, I'm doing even more...
I can make peace a reality.
お前　本気で言ってんのか？　それ。
Are you really serious?
Do you really believe that?
本当の本当に　そう思ってんのか？
((オビト：リンが俺を
救ってくれるってことは→
You know, Rin, you saving me...
is really the same as
you saving the world.
つまり　それは世界を
救うってことと同じなんだよな。
（リン）えっ？
だって　ほら→
Hmm?
I mean...
It's because I'm gonna become
the Hokage and end this war!
俺は　火影になって
この戦争を終わらせるわけだろ。
For me to do that,
それには
俺が　この世に元気でいないと！
I have to stay strong and
healthy in this world.
意味　わかる？
You get what I'm saying?
Yeah! Though you're not
making much sense...
うん！　わかりにくいけど。
それには　やっぱ　なんていうの？
So...how do I put it...?
俺のこと　ずっとそばで
見ておいてくれないと…。
If you don't stay close
and keep an eye on me...
つまり…　その…。
I mean...
Well...
うわっ！
えっ？
Y-You got so close all of a sudden!
だって　いきなり近すぎるからさ！
ビックリしちまうだろ！
Don't scare me like that!
そばで見ておいてくれって
言ったでしょ。　フフフフッ！
You just said to stay close
and keep an eye on you?
Yeah, I did.
（オビト）ああ　言ったさ！
見ててくれ！
So watch over me.
俺は　うちはの紋章を背負って→
I'm going to wear the Uchiha crest...
And definitely become the Hokage!
必ず火影になるんだ！
(うん！))
Okay!
そうだ…　そう思っている。
Yes... That's how I feel.
行き先もはっきりせず→
There's no need to voluntarily tread
a steep and rugged path,
わざわざ険しい道だと
わかっていて歩くことはない。
not knowing what's ahead.
仲間の死体をまたぐだけだ。
You'll have to step over
the corpses of your comrades.
はっきりした行き先があり→
Anyone would choose a shortcut
with a fixed outcome.
近道があるなら
誰でもそちらを選ぶ。
そう　火影の目指すべき行き先は
世界の平和だ。
Yes.
The goal a Hokage should
seek is world peace.
なに言ってんだ　お前。
What the hell are you talking about?
俺が知りてぇのは
楽な道のりじゃねえ。
What I want to know about
isn't a shortcut...
険しい道の歩き方だ！
but how to navigate
the steep and rugged path!
その２つの道の行き先が
同じだとしても→
Would you still say that
if the final destination...
そう思うのか？
were the same?
一方が険しい道だって
最初に誰が教えてくれんだよ？
Who can tell in the beginning
which one is the dangerous one?
結局　誰かが歩かなきゃ
それも　わかんねえだろうが。
You never know until
someone starts walking.
火影ってのは　痛ぇの我慢して→
The Hokage is someone
who endures the pain
みんなの前を
歩いているヤツのことだ。
and takes the lead in front
of everyone...
だから仲間の死体を
またぐようなことは→
So a Hokage never walks
over his comrades' corpses.
決して　ねえ！
火影になるヤツに近道はねえし
なったヤツに逃げ道はねえんだよ。
There is no shortcut to
becoming the Hokage!
And there are no ways out for
the one who becomes Hokage!
そうだろ？
Isn't that right?
((オビト：ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
《やべぇ　やべぇ　やべぇ！
Oh man, oh man, oh man!
今日だけは
遅刻するわけにはいかねえんだ》
This is the one day I can't be late!
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
ENTRANCE CEREMONY
Where should we go?
I don't know, where should we go?
これから楽しみだよね。
どこ行く　どこ行く？
Where do you want to go?
（カカシ）入学式から遅刻か。
It's the entrance ceremony
and you're already late...
そんなヤツに
アカデミーに入る資格はない。
Someone like you has no business
being in the Academy.
無理だな。
（リン）大丈夫よ！
You'll never make it.
It's okay.
NINJA ACADEMY
ENTRANCE REGISTRATION
これ　ちゃ～んと
もらっておいたから。
I got this for you.
お…　俺の！？
F-For me?
Yes! Just submit this and
you'll be able to enroll.
（リン）ええ　この書類を出せば
問題なく入学できるって。
助かった　恩にきるぜ！
Thank you! You're a lifesaver!
チェッ　甘やかしてっと
コイツの遅刻グセ　直んねえぞ。
Keep pampering him and
he'll never be cured of his tardiness.
うるせぇ　やるか　この！
Shut up! Do you wanna fight?
（カカシ）なにを！？
（オビト）なんだよ！
Say that again!
What?!
（カカシ）お前が悪いんだろうが。
（オビト）なんだと　バカカシ！
It's your fault!
What did you say, Kakashi?!
チッ！
１０点満点！
A perfect score of 10!
Wow, amazing!
かっこいい！
こっち向いて！
すごい！
コラーッ　殺す気か！
Hey! Are you trying to kill me?!
すみません！
S-Sorry!
もうやだ！
始め！
Begin!
そこまで！
Stop right there!
は　はい！
Y-Yes!
え～と　え～と…。
Um...um...
どうした　オビト？　指してないぞ。
What is it, Obito?
I didn't call on you.
今のおかしい！
That was so funny!
He's so weird!
(当ててないのにね))
((えっ　カカシが卒業試験を
受けるのか？
Kakashi's taking
the graduation exam?
うん。
でも　アイツ同い年だろ？
Yeah!
But he's the same age as us.
優秀だから
飛び級が決まったんだって。
He's brilliant,
so he's skipping a level!
ちょうど
試験を受けてるところよ。
He should be taking
the exam just about now.
クソーッ！
Damn it!
– Wow!
It's amazing!
お前　その額あては…。
合格したのね！　おめでとう。
What's with that headband?
You passed!
Congratulations!
ああ。
Yeah...
（カカシ）なんだ
祝ってくれないのか？
Aren't you going to congratulate me?
誰が！
すぐに追いついてやるからな！
As if! I'll catch up to you in no time!
覚えてろ！！
Just you wait!
オビト…。
Obito...
授業が始まるよ。　行こう。
Class is starting. Let's go.
リン…。
Rin...
俺を…　俺を見ててくれよな。
Keep...
Keep watching over me, okay?
えっ？
Huh?
（オビト）俺…　アイツに追いつくから。
I...
I'll catch up to him!
そんで　追い抜いて…
必ず火影になるから。
Then I'll surpass him and...
I'll become the Hokage,
no matter what!
うん　大丈夫。　ちゃんと見てるよ。
Yes. Don't worry, I'll be watching.
よっしゃ！！　頑張るぞ！
All right!
I'm gonna do my best!
むむむ…。
ハァハァ…。
《あんなんじゃ　ダメだ！
No good...
ダメだ…　落ちたに決まってる！
It's no good.
Of course I totally failed...
ダメだ…　まだ追いつけないのかよ》
Damn it...
I still can't catch up to him...
はぁ～。
俺　リンになんて言えばいいんだよ。
What do...I say to Rin?
なんだ　こんなとこにいたのか。
So there you are!
勝手に教室　飛び出して。
You just dashed out
of the classroom.
すみません。
I-I'm sorry.
捜したぞ。　ほい！
I looked all over you.
Here you go!
あ…　まさか　俺…。
Don't tell me I...?
おめでとう！　今日から　めでたく
一人前の忍になったわけだ。
Congratulations! From today,
you are a full-fledged shinobi.
やった！
I did it!
しかし　下忍が大変なのは
これからだぞ！
However...!
The difficult days as
a Genin are just beginning!
は　はい！
Y-Yes!
今後は　スリーマンセルの班に編成され→
Hereafter, you will be part
of a three-man squad.
各班ごとに１人ずつ
上忍の先生がついて→
Each cell has a Jonin in command
and you will fulfill
your missions as a team.
任務をこなしていく。
（ミナト）失礼します。
Excuse me.
（ミナト）お呼びですか？
You wanted to see me?
（ヒルゼン）お前に頼みたいことがある。
I want to ask you a favor.
今　出ていったのは
たしか　はたけカカシ。
The one who just left...
Isn't he Kakashi Hatake?
ああ…　木ノ葉の白い牙
はたけサクモの忘れ形見だ。
Yes...
The White Fang of the Hidden Leaf...
Sakumo Hatake's orphaned son.
彼に何か問題が？
Is there an issue with him?
はたけカカシは　優秀な忍だ。
Kakashi Hatake is
an extremely talented shinobi.
しかし　ルールに厳密なあまり
配属されたどの班でも→
However, he fusses too much
about sticking to the rules
and clashes with his superiors
and teammates.
先輩や同僚とぶつかり
問題を起こす。
いかに　技が優れていようが
人間としては　まだまだ未熟だ。
He may excel in technique,
but as a human
he has much to learn.
ルールを破り仲間を守ったため→
His father broke the rules
to protect his comrades,
then took his own life...
自ら命を絶った父親の死が
影を落としているのだろう。
His death has cast a shadow
over Kakashi.
それで　私に預かれと？
And you want to place him
under my supervision...
言いたいことはわかっておる。
I know what you want to say.
だが　長引く戦いに
里の上忍　中忍たちの多くが→
But our village has lost
many Jonin and Chunin
due to the long war.
失われてしまった。
多少のことは目をつぶっても→
I can make an allowance
only so much,
若者たちを戦場へ送らねばならぬ。
and I must send
the young ones to war.
わかりました。
I understand.
ったくもう
いつまで待たせるんだよ？
Goodness! How long will
you keep me waiting?!
すみません　もうすぐ来ますから。
I beg your pardon!
He'll be here shortly.
アイツの遅刻グセは相変わらずだな。
As usual, he's late.
大丈夫　すぐ来るよ。
Don't worry. He'll be here.
やっぱリンは甘すぎだな。
You're too easy on him, Rin.
遅くなりました。
Sorry I'm late!
リン？
Rin?
遅い！
You're late!
ったく　いつもこれだな。
Damn it... It's always like this.
なに！
What did you say?!
おっと！　はいはい
そのへんにしてくれる？
げんぞうさんがお待ちかねだよ。
早く並んで。
いいかね？　こっちを見て。
フンッ！
(記念写真なんだから　レンズを見て))
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
オープニングを飾るのは　この曲です。